やりたいことが
よくわかりません｡
最強の兵器であるさん…➡
ｵﾚも わかりません｡
いまだ
こういうﾊｶﾞｷが来る 体たらく…｡
｢『銀魂』は 何がしたいのですか？
このｱﾆﾒの ｺﾞｰﾙが見当たりません｣｡
いやぁ ２年半もやってんのに➡
最強の兵器であるさんの質問｡
ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』のｺﾞｰﾙは
｢侍王になる！｣です｡
いっそ どっかで
｢侍王になる！｣➡
はい ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘ お答えしましょう｡
目標もなく ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗ
続けるもんじゃねえよ まったく｡
とか 言っときゃよかったかな～｡
あっ そうしよう｡
はい そんなわけで
ｷｬｻﾘﾝのﾈｺ耳は 史上最悪➡
(銀時)え～ ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ…
[Teach us!! Ginpachi Sensei]
Teach us!
Ginpachi Sensei
Pen name "Catherine's cat ears are the worst-ever,
strongest-ever weapons" writes...
"What is "GinTama" trying to do?
I don't understand what they're doing.
I don't see any kind of goal in this anime."
Okay, here's your answer.
I don't know, either.
It's sad that after two-and-a-half years,
we're still getting postcards like this.
We shouldn't keep dragging
on and on. I mean really.
Maybe I should've said something like "I'm
going to become the Samurai King!"
[Note: Parody of ONE PIECE.]
So let's use that.
And so, "Catherine's cat ears are the
worst-ever, strongest-ever weapons,"
[Note: Gintoki is wearing Luffy's
costume from ONE PIECE.]
the goal of GinTama the anime is:
"to become the Samurai King!"
[Cattle abduction. In essence: the
kidnapping of livestock by aliens.]
[Oh, scary!! Aliens are so scary!!]
["Novices Only Need a Flathead and a Phillips"]
(草野)画面中央をご覧ください｡
Look at the center of your screen.
ｶﾒﾗが遠く はっきりとは
確認できませんが➡
Our camera is too far
away to see it clearly.
But you can see what
appears to be a cow
確かに 牛らしき動物が➡
flying through the air as if it's
being sucked into the sky.
空に吸い寄せられるように
飛んでいくのが見えます｡
仕事してたらよう…➡
[Livestock farmer Zenshichi Toyobe (Age 72)]
I was working, when all of
a sudden, the sky lit up.
突然 空が
ﾋﾟｶｯと光ってよう…｡
そしたら 空に
光る円盤が飛んでて➡
A glowing saucer came flying down,
sucked up my cow and flew off.
うちの牛を吸い込んで
飛んでっちまったんだ｡
隣の彦八のとこも
豚 全部…➡
I hear Hikohachi over yonder
had all of his pigs taken, too.
かっさらわれたって話だべ｡
いったい誰が
こんなﾏﾈば しくさってんだ？
Who could be doing such a thing?
(草野)幕府では これを
天人による盗難事件ととらえ➡
The Bakufu suspects these to be
cases of theft by Amanto thieves
現在 調査を行っています｡
and is conducting an investigation.
今のところ 被害は 農村の
家畜にしか出ていませんが➡
Currently, the only damage has been
to livestock in farming villages,
都市部にお住まいの皆さんも
念のため➡
but for anybody living in the city-we urge
you to lock your doors and be on the alert.
戸締まりには 用心してください｡
さて 次のﾆｭｰｽです｡
In other news...
(新八)物騒ですね｡
今どきの泥棒は➡
How troubling. No telling where thieves
will strike from these days.
どっから来るか
わかったもんじゃないすよ｡
今どき ｷｬﾄﾙﾐｭｰﾃｨﾚｰｼｮﾝなんざ
流行んねえっつうのな～｡
Cattle abduction in this
day and age isn't cool.
今はねえけど 昔… 天人の存在が
知られる前なんかはさぁ…➡
A long time ago, before anyone
knew Amanto existed,
人間が かっさらわれて… 体を
勝手に改造されたりとか➡
human beings were abducted and their
bodies altered against their will.
そういうのもあったらしいから
神隠し… とか言われてよう…｡
Because of incidents like that, people
talked about being "spirited away."
厄介なのがよう…
そのときの記憶は➡
The problem was the victims had their
memories of the experience erased
消されてるもんだから
さらわれた当事者も➡
so they can't remember
what was done to them.
何されたか 覚えてねえんだよ｡
まぁ まれに覚えてるﾔﾂもいて
こんな話が残ってんだが…｡
But there were a rare few who did remember
and that's why we have these stories today.
まったく ｱｲﾂら 何やってるか
知れたもんじゃねえよ｡
There's no telling what
those bastards did.
実際 ｵﾒｴも
すでに さらわれてて➡
For all you know, you may have
already been abducted
体に 変なもんとか
埋め込まれてても➡
and had some strange thing
embedded in your body.
おかしくねえぜ｡
さらいやすそうだもんな お前｡
After all, you seem like an easy target.
ﾊﾊﾊﾊ… 冗談よしてくださいよ｡
Stop joking. I'm not a kid, so
you're not going to scare me.
子供じゃないんだから
ﾋﾞﾋﾞﾘませんよ そんなもんで…｡
銀さん…➡
(ﾃﾚﾋﾞの ﾉｲｽﾞ)
Gin-san, the TV's acting up again.
また ﾃﾚﾋﾞ 調子おかしいですよ｡
しようがねえなぁ ﾎﾝﾄによ～｡
This thing is hopeless...really.
That didn't fix it.
Maybe its time has come.
あれ？ 直んねえな…
いよいよ 寿命か？
ｺｲﾂも 中開いて
改造しなきゃいけねえのか？
Guess we'll have to open it up to fix it.
あっ 銀さん！
修理するなら ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰ…➡
Gin-san, if you're going to fix it,
I have a screwdriver...right here.
ここにありますよ｡ 使います？
Want to use it?
って… なっ ななな
何じゃ こりゃああ～!!
W-Wh-What is t-th-this?!
なななな… なんで ﾎﾞｸの指が
ﾌﾟﾗｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰに～!?
W-Wh-Why is my finger
a Phillips screwdriver?!
おい 新八…
いくら ｷｬﾗ弱いからって➡
C'mon Shinpachi, I know
your character is weak,
そりゃないわ～｡
ｷｬﾗ補正すんなら➡
but that's not the way to go.
[Note: From the anime Cobra.]
If you're going to upgrade your character,
at least give yourself a Psycho Gun.
腕 ｻｲｺｶﾞﾝにするとか
それくらいしねえとよ～➡
中途半端だって｡
違うわ～っ!!
That's so half-assed.
That's not what happened!
ｷｬﾗ補正で
誰が こんなﾏﾈすっか～!!
Who'd do something like this
to upgrade their character?!
身に覚えがねえってのか？
あるわけないでしょ！
You saying you don't remember
doing that?
Of course not! Who would choose
to do such a thing?!
誰が すき好んで
こんなことするんすか！
知らないうちに
そんなことになってたって…｡
You're saying you have no
idea how it got there?
おいおい ｷｬﾄﾙﾐｭｰﾃｨﾚｰｼｮﾝでも
されたってのか？
Did you get abducted?
まっ まさか…｡
Could...it be...
あれは 夢じゃなかったのか？
That wasn't a dream?
((今日の晩ご飯は ｻﾝﾏだな｡
Tonight, I'm having Pacific
saury for dinner.
[Note: Pacific saury (mackerel
pike) is a type of fish.]
秋は やっぱり ｻﾝﾏに限るよね｡
Nothing beats saury in the fall.
えっ… なっ 何だ？
Wh...What is that?
♪♪～
あれは… まぶしい！
It's...
so bright!
(天人)どうですかね？ これ…｡
How's this one?
(天人)また ﾀﾞﾒだ…
これ やっぱ お前 ちょっと➡
No good again.
The size is too big.
It doesn't fit the screw.
ｻｲｽﾞでかすぎたなぁ
ﾈｼﾞと合わねえわ～｡
まいったな
これじゃ 修理できねえよ PS…｡
Good grief, now I can't fix my PS(P).
ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸ 壊れちゃってさ
ﾓﾝﾊﾝやってたら｡
The analog controller broke while
I was playing Mon-Hun.
[Note: Short for PSP game Monster Hunter Portable.
Sold as Monster Hunter Freedom in US.]
分解したら たぶん 絶対 簡単に
直ると思うんだよね～ これ｡
I'm positive it'd be an easy
fix if I took it apart.
やっぱ 素人が勝手に 分解とか
やめたほうがいいですって｡
I don't think an amateur
should disassemble it.
修理に出しましょう ｿﾞﾆｰに｡
Let's send it to Zony for repair.
[Note: Parody of Sony.]
(天人)いや でも
金とかとられたらｲﾔじゃん｡
I don't want someone taking my money.
(天人)いや でも…
１回 勝手に分解しちゃったら➡
But I heard if you disassemble it yourself,
they won't accept it for repair.
もう 修理とか
請け負ってくれないらしいっすよ｡
(天人)えっ ﾏｼﾞで!?
What? Seriously?
買ったときに付いてた
保証書みたいなのは➡
What'd you do with the warranty...
that came with it when you bought it?
どこやったんすか？
あれ たぶん…➡
I probably...
箱と一緒に捨てたわ やべ～｡
threw it out with the box, uh-oh...
うわぁ～!!
W-Wh-What are you?!
なんですか ｱﾝﾀら～!?
ど… どこですか？ ここ～！
Wh-What is this place?
やべ 起きた｡
ｵﾒｴが でかい声出すから｡
Uh-oh, he's awake. It's because
you talk too loud.
えっ… 先輩が大きな声
出したんじゃないすか！
That was you, Senpai.
えっ!? わぁぁぁ～!!
ちょ… これ ﾎﾞｸの指…
何ですか？ これぇ!?
What...did you do to my finger?!
いや ｵﾚたち 知らないよ｡
We don't know anything about that.
知らねえじゃねえだろ！
お前 これ…➡
What do you mean you don't know?!
You...it's...a Phillips screwdriver now!
ﾌﾟﾗｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰになってんだろうが～!!
え～ 最初から
そんなんだったよ｡
It was like that from the start.
ｳｿ ぶっこいてんじゃねえ!!
ｵﾒｴらだろ これ！
Don't lie! You did this!
You modified my body!
人の体 勝手に改造したろう!?
違うんすよ
ｵﾚは ｲﾔだって言ったんすよ｡
We didn't. I didn't want to.
先輩がなんか PS…
分解したいとか言い出して｡
Then Senpai said he wanted
to take apart the PS(P).
PS…!?
だからお前 言うなや！
PS(P)?!
I told you not to say anything!
Hey, what do you mean by PS(P)?! Is that
the reason why you...?!
おい！
PS…って どういうことだ!?
ﾃﾒｴら まさか
そんなことのために!?
いや 違うんだって その➡
No, that's not it at all. We didn't
have the right screwdriver, so...
ちょうどいい感じの
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰなくてね…｡
That's totally it!
違わねえだろ！
そんなもん そのへんの➡
You could've bought something
like that at any hardware shop.
ﾎｰﾑｾﾝﾀｰで
買ってくればいいだろうが！
Why did you have to modify my body?!
なんで 人体改造
しなくちゃならねえんだよ！
(天人)いや 違うんだよ
事は一刻を争うからさぁ…｡
No, you misunderstand.
We had no time to lose...
だってさ ｵﾒｴがさ
ぜってえさ➡
After all, I knew you'd
try to get ahead of me
ｵﾚが ﾓﾝﾊﾝやれない間に
お前 抜けがけすんじゃん｡
in Mon-Hun while I couldn't play.
ぜってえ ｵﾒｴさ
一人で ﾊﾟｵｼｬﾝﾛﾝとか倒して➡
You'd defeat Paoshanron all by yourself
to get an awesome item
[Note: Paoshanron is a Parody of Lao
Shan Lung from Monster Hunter.]
いい素材 手に入れてｵﾒｴ
先輩ﾂﾞﾗするつもりだろ あん？
and give me the "I'm better
than you" Senpai look.
え？ いや
やりませんって｡
I wouldn't do that.
I'd never be able to defeat
Paoshanron by myself.
ﾊﾟｵｼｬﾝﾛﾝなんか
一人じゃ倒せませんもん｡
お前さ 前もそんなこと言って
ｵﾚが知らねえ間に お前➡
You told me that last time.
一人で ﾌﾟﾘﾝ倒しに行って
いい装備なってたじゃん お前｡
Then you defeated Purin alone
and got a nice item.
[Note: Parody of Kirin from Monster Hunter.]
Seriously unbelievable.
ﾏｼﾞ ありえねえんだけど｡
Who cares?! What're you going
to do about my finger?!
どうでもいいわ！
おい これ どうしてくれんだよ!!
Return it to normal! I'll sue you!
I'll definitely file charges!
これ 元に戻せよ！ 訴えるぞ！
お前ら 絶対 告訴してやる！
どうします 先輩？
いやもう PS… あきらめるわ｡
What should we do, Senpai?
I'll give up on the PS(P).
(天人)最近 あの
新しいの 出たっていうじゃん｡
There's supposed to
be a new model out.
あの ﾈｯﾄのﾔﾂ
そっち やろうぜ｡
The one that's Net-enabled.
Let's play that one.
(天人)あぁ あれなんか
PS…のﾃﾞｰﾀも➡
You're supposed to be able to
transfer your PS(P) data to it.
引き継げるらしいっすよ｡
ｺｲﾂはどうします？
What'll we do about him?
Throw him out onto the road.
(天人)そんなもん
そのまま道に捨てとけ))
じゃあ 何 お前
PS…の修理のために➡
So you're saying they abducted
you to modify your finger
into a screwdriver just so they
could repair their PS(P)?
ｷｬﾄﾙﾐｭｰﾃｨﾚｰｼｮﾝされて
指 ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰに改造されたんだ｡
ｸｸｸｸ…｡
おい こっち向けよ｡
Hey, look at me.
It's not funny! How am I supposed
to live with a finger like this?
笑いごとじゃねえんだよ！
こんな指で いったい
ﾎﾞｸはこれから➡
どうやって生活
していけばいいんですか！
I can't pick my nose or
hug the person I love!
鼻をほじることも
愛する人を抱きしめることも➡
できやしないんですよ！
You'll be fine.
大丈夫だよ
愛する人の心のﾈｼﾞを➡
You'll be able to tighten the screws
to the heart of the person you love.
締めてやることは
できるだろ｡
That's just lousy smooth talk.
何 うまいこといって
うやむやにしようとしてんだ｡
なんだ 心のﾈｼﾞって！
気にすんじゃねえよ｡
What do you mean "screws
to the heart"?
Forget it. You have ten fingers.
指なんて お前
10本もあるんだよ｡
I'm sure it's more convenient that
one of them is a screwdriver.
１本くらい ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰのほうが
便利だって絶対｡ 小便いってくる｡
I've got to pee.
Don't say irresponsible things because
it's someone else's problem!
人ごとだと思って いい加減なこと
言わないでください！
(神楽)う～す｡
あっ 神楽ちゃん➡
'Morning.
Oh, Kagura-chan, look what
happened to my finger...
ちょっと見てよ これ
ﾎﾞｸの指が…｡
I had a weird dream and
didn't sleep very well.
(神楽)なんか 変な夢みて
あんま眠れなかったよ｡
銀さん!! 神楽ちゃんが!!
Gin-san! It's Kagura-chan!
神楽ちゃんが 全身
ﾏｲﾅｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰに改造されてます!!
Kagura-chan's entire body's been
turned into a flathead screwdriver!
ちょっと 聞いてます!?
銀さん!?
C'mon! Are you listening?! Gin-san?
銀さん？
Gin-san?!
…銀さん？
...Gin-san?
《まさか…》
Not you, too...!
G-Gin-san...n-not you, too?
ぎ 銀さん… ま まさか…｡
ﾌｯ… ぱっつぁんよ｡
Patsuan, it's not a crime to kill
aliens from outer space, right?
宇宙人って殺しても
罪にならないよね｡
They did it to him! They messed
with Gin-san's analog stick!
《やられた!! 銀さんの
ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸがやられた!!》
[Net Cafe]
残念ながら ﾔﾂらに関する情報は
極めて少ない｡
Unfortunately, the information we have
on them is extremely limited.
どこの星の天人かも
今 どこにいるかもわからない｡
We don't know what planet those Amanto
are from, or where they are now.
わかっているのは ﾔﾂらが
ﾓﾝﾊﾝに はまってることだけです｡
All we know is that they're
obsessed with Mon-Hun.
ここから
ﾔﾂらの尻尾をつかみ➡
Our only hope is to find a clue
and trace it back to them.
手繰りよせるしか
ありません｡
What is "Mon-Hun"? Is that short
for Mongolian hamster?
なにｱﾙか ﾓﾝﾊﾝって｡
ﾓﾝｺﾞﾘｱﾝﾊﾑｽﾀｰ ｱﾙか？
今 銀河じゅうで
大流行のｹﾞｰﾑだよ｡
It's a very popular game throughout
the galaxy right now.
MONKEY HUNTER 通称ﾓﾝﾊﾝ｡
Monkey Hunter, a.k.a. Mon-Hun.
[Note: Parody of the game, Monster Hunter.]
ﾌﾟﾚｲﾔｰは ﾊﾝﾀｰとなって➡
It's a game where the player enjoys
being a hunter on a planet inhabited
さまざまな
怪物ｻﾞﾙが 生息する星を舞台に➡
ﾊﾝﾀｰﾗｲﾌを楽しむｹﾞｰﾑです｡
by many types of monster monkeys.
ﾔﾂらは PS…版を
やっていたようですが➡
They were playing the PS(P) version
最新作のｵﾝﾗｲﾝに
移り気していた｡
and wanted to switch to
the latest online version.
これが運がよかった｡
That's fortunate for us.
ｵﾝﾗｲﾝ版は
ﾈｯﾄ上に作られたﾌｨｰﾙﾄﾞに➡
The online version allows gamers
from all over the galaxy
銀河じゅうのｹﾞｰﾏｰたちが
ｱｸｾｽして遊んでいます｡
to access a playing field
created on the Net.
ﾔﾂらが 宇宙のどこにいようと➡
No matter where those aliens are,
ｹﾞｰﾑ内で網を張っていれば
必ず会えます｡
if we conduct our search inside the game,
we're bound to meet up with them.
So we'll have to search for
them inside the game
銀河じゅうのｹﾞｰﾏｰが
集まってるｹﾞｰﾑ内で➡
where gamers from across
the galaxy come together.
ﾔﾂらを探すｱﾙか｡
面倒ｱﾙな｡
That'll be troublesome.
しかたないじゃないか
何の手がかりもない上で➡
We don't have a choice.
We don't have any other clues,
確実に あのｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人が
あん!?
来そうなところは…｡
so this is the only place we can be sure
those game-playing aliens will be.
Huh?
We don't have to go through
all that hassle.
んな まどろっこしいこと
しねえでもよ➡
こっちで天人 かたっぱしから
ﾊﾝﾄしたほうが早くねえ？
It'd be faster if we hunted down
every single Amanto.
１匹ずつ
なぶり殺しにしていこうぜ｡
I'll give everyone of them
a slow and painful death.
Gin-san's losing it.
Do something, Kagura-chan.
銀さんの荒み方が
半端じゃないんだけど｡
神楽ちゃん なんとかして｡
Damn right, I'm losing it!
そりゃ 荒みもすんだろうがよ!!
新八 ｵﾒｴはいいよな➡
Shinpachi, you were lucky.
10本ある ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸのうち➡
Of your ten analog sticks, only one
got turned into a screwdriver.
たかが １本
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰになっただけなんだから｡
ｵﾚはよ この世に１本しかねえ
超ﾚｱな ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸ➡
I, on the other hand, have only
one in the entire world,
an extremely rare analog stick...
いや… ｼﾞｮｲｽﾃｨｯｸを
おしゃかにされたんだぞ あん？
No, joystick...and now it's useless! Eh?
Gin-san, you're too loud.
銀さん 声でかいです｡
しかもよ➡
And what's worse, they changed
it into a kind of screwdriver
何か 見たこともねえﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰに
変えられてんだけど 何あれ？
I've never seen before!
What is that? Huh?
ﾎﾞｯｸｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰですね たぶん｡
It's probably a hex socket screwdriver.
Where am I supposed to use this?!
どこで使えばいいんだよ
あれよぉ!!
使いどころが
わかんねえんだよ！
I have no idea!
They could've at least made
it a Phillips or a flathead!
せめて ﾌﾟﾗｽかﾏｲﾅｽくらいに
してくれてもいいだろうが!!
Your stick never had any use, anyway.
もともと 銀ちゃんのなんて
使いみちのないｽﾃｨｯｸだったｱﾙ｡
腐って
落ちたほうがよかったﾈ｡
It would've been better if it had
corroded and fallen off.
ﾏｲﾅｽﾄﾞﾗｲﾊﾞｰのお前に
ﾎﾞｯｸｽの気持なんかわからねえよ｡
A flathead like you would
never understand
how a hex socket like me feels!
絶対 許さねえ！
They won't get away with this...
ｱｲﾂら 電脳空間から
引きずり出して➡
I'll drag them out of cyberspace and
tear their analog sticks apart!
ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸ
八つ裂きにしてやる｡
I swear...I swear I'll get my stick back.
必ず… 必ず
元の体を取り戻してやる！
行くぜ ﾃﾒｴら!!
はい！
Let's go, you guys!
Right!
…じゃあ 混んでるから
ﾎﾞｸは あっち｡
It's crowded here, so I'll go that way,
神楽ちゃんは あっちで｡
and Kagura-chan, you go that way!
We'll meet at the designated place!
集合場所で 会いましょう｡
ﾗｼﾞｬ～！
Roger!
＜ そして ﾎﾞｸらは…➡
And so began our battle
to restore our bodies.
元の体を 取り戻す戦いは…
始まった！＞
♪♪～
The curtain is about to rise...
A spectacular battle for survival.
A hunter trusts only...
Himself.
Beat them down...
Or dazzle them with your technique.
Monkey Hunter online!
[Note: Parody of a Monster Hunter
online TV commercial.]
Risk your life to hunt them down!
[New Game
Load]
Welcome to the world of Monkey Hunter.
(ＰＣの声)MONKEY HUNTERの世界へ
ようこそ｡
ここは 銀河じゅうのﾊﾝﾀｰたちが
集まる 夢の冒険空間です｡
This is the adventure of your dreams where
hunters from all across the galaxy gather.
くれぐれも ﾈｯﾄﾏﾅｰを守り➡
Please exercise proper Netiquette
to ensure this is an enjoyable
experience for all.
誰もが 心地よい空間になるよう
ご協力ください｡
それでは この世界での➡
All right, please create your
avatar for this world.
あなたの 分身となる存在を➡
お決めください｡
そうか…｡
I see. I have to start by creating
自分の ｷｬﾗの設定から
始めなきゃ いけないんだ…｡
銀さんたち
ちゃんと やれてるかな…｡
I wonder if Gin-san and
Kagura are doing okay.
う～ん…
本名は やめたほうが いいよね｡
I shouldn't use my real name.
My avatar needs...
ｷｬﾗは…｡
♪♪～
おっ！ ﾒｶﾞﾈ｡
Oh yes, glasses.
Okay, I'll go with this.
よし！ ﾎﾞｸは これで いこう！
Sure looks like me. How common
is my appearance?
結構 似てるな～｡
どんだけ 単純なﾊﾟｰﾂで
できてるんだ ﾎﾞｸは…｡
♪♪～
Wow, there sure are a lot of people.
They're all players of this
game. Awesome.
きっと この中に ﾔﾂらが…｡
Those aliens are definitely
in here somewhere.
絶対 探し出して
元の体に 戻るぞ～！
I'll find them and restore my body!
それより 銀さんたち遅いな～｡
Gin-san and Kagura are late. I told
them to meet me at this spot.
集会所前で 待ち合わせって
言ったのに…｡
Hi.
Someone approached me.
おっ 誰か 話しかけてきた｡
It's a girl.
女の子だ！
Are you a beginner at this game?
I'm a beginner, too.
What do you say? Would you
like to go hunting with me?
わぁ～ 誘われちゃったよ…
どうしよう…｡
Wow! She invited me. What'll I do?
なに これ～!?
なんか 変な気分なんですけど…｡
What is this awkward feeling?
It's as if she's asking me out.
逆ﾅﾝされたみたいな…｡
What should I do? I feel
kinda happy, though.
どうしよう…｡
やべえ ちょっと嬉しい！
No...but Gin-san and
Kagura are here, too.
いや…
でも 銀さんたちが いるしな…｡
I can't go girl-hunting.
I don't have a choice.
女の子を
狩りに来たわけじゃないし…｡
しようがない…｡
I'm sorry. I'm expecting someone.
I see. Too bad...
Oh, by the way, I'm in a bind right now.
Would you mind giving me an item?
I wouldn't mind, but I just started the
game myself, so I don't have much.
That's all right. It's an item everyone has.
Give me your balls!
銀さ～ん!!
Gin-san?!
Are you still hung up over
your analog stick?!
ｱﾅﾛｸﾞｽﾃｨｯｸ
まだ 引きずってるよ～!!
Give them to me, I said!
Hey! He keeps punching
me in the crotch!
ちょっ… めっちゃ
股間 攻撃してきてるよ！
Stop it! Gin-san, we're
comrades! Come on!
This is a game where we
defeat the monkeys
and take their items to strengthen
our armaments!
What're you trying to take?!
Shut up, four-eyed monkey!
You're totally in a "take-your-anger-out-on-anyone" mood, dammit.
Pisses me off.
How long are you going to
feel sorry for yourself?
You lost your analog stick, so
now you're an online tranny?!
Are you stupid or something?
I didn't create this avatar because
I was down on myself.
Listen, we're not here to play around.
We're here to find those
rotten Amanto, right?
情報収集には ﾑｻい男より➡
Isn't this form more suitable
for gathering information
than some shabby dude?
こういうほうが
向いてるだろうが！
I see! Just what I'd expect
of you, Gin-san!
そうか！ さすが 銀さん！
Gamers are gonna be kids who
are wet behind the ears,
desperate for girls, and stuck
in a room littered with tissues.
I figure if I went with a sexy
look, they'd be pushovers.
Now then, time to gather
some information.
How 'bout this?
Lets look for strong-looking veterans who've
been playing this game a long time.
あっ！ あれなんて
いいんじゃないですか？
Oh!
That guy over there looks good.
ﾒﾁｬﾒﾁｬ 強そうですよ！
He looks really strong.
He's probably played over 100 hours.
確実に 100時間以上 やってます！
Excuse me, can I ask you a question?
What is it?
It's you!
That you, Gin-chan?
Why does someone who just started playing
look like a veteran warrior?
What's that scar on your face?
Who gave you that?
Kagura-chan, where'd you
get those fine weapons?
I'm a hunter. I get what
I want from the hunt.
Hunt? But you just started.
How did you...?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry. We've already
formed our party.
We don't need any more members.
No, we're the administrators
of this game.
We received a report that
a hunter was attacked
and stripped of his clothes and equipment
in a back alley nearby.
Do you know anything about it?
(管理者)何か 知りませんか？
Ugh!
Don't rob them!
Mmm... Looks Tasty!
[Note: Parody of Monster Hunter. "Mmm... Looks Tasty!"
voice is heard when player barbecues a well-done steak.]
(管理者)上手に 焼けました～!!
Don't barbeque him!
What're you doing?!
This is a game where you hunt monkeys!
It's not a game where
hunters hunt hunters!
First-rate hunters aren't picky
about their targets.
You guys aren't hunters!
You're nothing but bandits!
Ack! Trouble!
ﾙｰﾙを犯したから管理者が怒って➡
The administrators are trying to oust
us because we broke the rules!
ﾎﾞｸらを
排除しようとしていますよ！
If they catch us, we'll never be able
to play this game again! Run!
逃げろ～！
♪♪～
A very interesting group
has joined the game.
どうするんですか？
What should we do?
[Patsuan - Hunter's knife wielder]
After what we did, we can't
return to the town.
どうやって ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人の情報を
聞き出すんですか？
[Ginko - Great sword wielder]
How're we going to gather information
about the alien gamers?
しかも こんなﾌｨｰﾙﾄﾞ出ちゃって
いつ ﾓﾝｷｰに襲われるか➡
And we're out in a field where
[Kaguura Jasuanto - Dual sword wielder]
there's no telling when the
monkeys might attack.
わかったもんじゃないですよ｡
Do you understand? Now that the
game administrators are after us,
if we lose and the game ends even once,
we'll never be able to access
this game again.
Shut up. I know that.
Kagura, your long sword has been
bumping against my knees.
It's getting in my way.
I'm not Kagura. I'm Kaguura Jasuanto.
[Note: Probably a wordplay on
Giant from André the Giant.]
What's a Kaguura Jasuanto?
Are you serious?
Sounds like a name a middle-schooler
would think of.
That's totally the failure pattern
of a novice sending in their entry
to a manga competition.
You know, the way they over-think
things to the point where
the readers can't remember
the name of the characters.
Shut up, Mr. No-balls!
(神楽)うるせえよ ﾀﾏなし！
What do you mean "Mr.
No-balls"?! Huh?!
I swear I'll restore my body
to the way it was!
Come on, both you-stop it.
Anyway, since we can't go back to town,
we have no choice but to
keep moving forward.
We'll keep hunting to the very end.
Hunt?
That's right. This is a game where the
players enjoy hunting the enemy.
If we go to a high-level area, we'll
find equally high-level hunters.
つまり長時間 このｹﾞｰﾑを遊んだ
さまざまな情報をもった➡
In other words, we'll be able
to meet all kinds of people
who've played this game
for tons of hours.
ﾌﾟﾚｲﾔｰに会えるんです
きっと ｹﾞｰﾏｰ星人のことを➡
We're bound to find hunters who
know about the alien Gamers.
知っているﾊﾝﾀｰがいるに違いない｡
Hey, aren't you the one who said
we're done for if the game ends?
Then we should become allies
with the hunters we meet.
We'll get information, and kill
two birds with one stone.
And if all goes well, we might even
bump into the alien Gamers.
Yes! We should start by making allies.
Excuse me. We're novices at this game.
Won't you play with us?
一緒にｹﾞｰﾑやりませんか？
Not that one! That's the enemy!
(ﾓﾝｷｰ)ｸﾞｫ～…！
Run!
Hurry! Hurry!
Gin-san! What item do we
need to get past him?
This was amongst the things we
took from the security squad!
ｼﾋﾞﾚﾊﾞﾅﾅ!?
A tainted banana?!
[Note: Parody of Tainted Meat
from Monster Hunter.]
I get it-if we throw this at the
monkey and get him to eat it,
he'll be paralyzed.
Okay, here!
Eat this!
ｶﾞｧ～…！
[Note: Now Loading background
is a parody of Monster Hunter.]
Why'd you eat it?!
It was a trap.
It's not a trap for you! It's a
trap meant for the beast!
ｵﾒｴに かけた罠じゃねえよ
獣の罠 それ！
Never mind me. Go quickly.
Become a good...hunter...
神楽ちゃん！
Kagura-chan!
Gin-san, at this rate, the game is
going to end for Kagura-chan.
Lure the enemy this way.
What's that...?!
A pit. We'll use these bananas
as bait and then pummel him.
落とし穴です このﾊﾞﾅﾅをｴｻに
罠にはめて ﾎﾞｺﾎﾞｺにしましょう｡
Over here, you stupid monkey!
Come here! That's it!
Yeah, we're right here!
(銀時/新八)
だから 何でお前がいるんだ!!
What are you doing here?!
How'd you get here when
you're paralyzed?!
What is this obsession you
have with bananas?!
At least in the game I get to eat my fill.
What a sorry thing to say.
You make me wanna cry!
I'm sorry...it's all my fault.
I'm so sorry.
Gin-san! The enemy!
ｸﾞｫ～…！
Who's that...?
♪♪～
[Teach us!! Ginpachi Sensei Encore]
Teach us!
Ginpachi Sensei
This time, we have a question
from pen name
"I can't watch in real time in Shizuoka city, so
I buy the DVDs and watch them instead."
"Who is the person that brush paints
the titles for each episode?
I looked in the credits
but couldn't find him.
They're beautifully written!"
Okay, here's your answer.
They're painted by a producer
at Sunrise named Wakanabe.
He studied calligraphy
when he was younger,
but then drank too much liquor.
That's why he can't write
the titles in a straight line.
Just FYI, he says he wouldn't mind
getting a hug from Joe Odagiri.
[Note: Joe Odagiri is a popular young actor.]
[Correct: "There's a Thin Line Between
Strengths and Weaknesses"]
In the preview for episode 102, he
made a mischievous mistake.
[Incorrect: Good Points and Bad
Points Are Hard to See]
Okay, Wakanabe,
so you don't get bigheaded because
someone praised your calligraphy,
go and stand out in the hall!
[Preview]
Yo! Kaguura Jasuanto here.
Next time, the sad story behind
the scar on my face and
the cursed bloodline that became
the reason for this journey of
revenge will be revealed!
No, it won't!
The next episode... "Imagination
Is Nurtured In the 8th Grade."
[In order to find hunter allies, the group
travels through the world of Mon-Hun.]
はい 今度はﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ 静岡市は➡
ﾘｱﾙﾀｲﾑで見れないので➡
[There, they find the legendary hunter, "M."]
DVD買って
見てますさんからの質問｡
｢毎回 ｻﾌﾞﾀｲﾄﾙの文字を
書いているのは誰ですか？
ﾃﾛｯﾌﾟを見ていても
よくわからないのですが➡
すごく いい字ですよね！｣
はい じゃあ ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘお答えします｡
あれは ｻﾝﾗｲｽﾞのﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰの
若鍋という人が書いています｡
昔 習字を
やっていたらしいんですが➡
酒の飲みすぎで
もう まっすぐの線が書けません｡
ちなみに ｵﾀﾞｷﾞﾘｼﾞｮｰなら
抱かれてもいいらしいです｡
あと 102話の予告では
ちょっと お茶目な➡
間違いなんか しちゃったりなんか
しちゃったりなんかしてます｡
じゃあ 若鍋！ 字 褒められて➡
調子に のりすぎないよう
廊下に立ってなさい！